Desonte Jolivet

Entry Level Software Developer

Summary

An experienced leader capable of working in stressful and volatile environments, with five years of experience training and mentoring soldiers during service in the military. Strong technical skills, with the ability to learn quickly. Proficient in Java and competent in HTML, JavaScript and CSS. Experience using Maven to create plugins and modular projects. Formulated and implemented plans for the development of web applications using GWT, Maven and J2EE technologies. My passion for learning and team oriented mentality are my greatest two traits.

Technical Skills

- Java
- JDBC
- J2EE (JPA, JAX-RS, Servlet, JSP)
- Maven
- GWT (Google Web Toolkit)
- SQL

Education

B.Sc in Computer Science

2014 - 2018

University of Hartford

Work experience

Senior Intelligence Analyst

2012 - 2013

US Army, 502D BN, Kandahar, Afghanistan

- Generated 56 intelligence reports and performed quality control on over 418 reports that were used to make real time battlefield decision by the battle space commander.
- "SPC Desonte played a key role in this capture (High Value Individual HVI, Kandahar Taliban SeniorLeadership) by providing the reporting that triggered the operation and ultimately provided fidelity required to capture the HVI" -CPT Hopper, Benjamin

Intelligence Analyst

2011 - 2012

US Army 502D BN, FT Lewis, WA

• Mentored junior analysts in intelligence community policies, standard and procedures in preparation for deployment to Afghanistan .

Intelligence Analyst

2009 - 2011

US Army, 24 MI BN, Wiesbaden, Germany

- "recognized by... EUCOM, CENTCOM and the State Department as being of significant high value and essential" -SFC Bobe, Jose Luis
- Maintained analytical working aids and databases.
- Managed a team of 4 analyst.
- Assisted in the production of over 319 intelligence products.

Links

- GitHub https://github.com/drjoliv
- WebStite: https://drjoliv.github.io/